Finding Aid for the Leo Smit Photograph Collection, circa 1926-1999
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Leo Smit Photograph Collection, circa 1926-1999
Mus. Arc. 6.3
Smit, Leo, 1921-1999
5 boxes (458 items)
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Chiefly black and white photographs documenting Leo Smit's life and career in music.
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Acquisition Information
The collection was in part a gift from Leo Smit in 1998. The remainder of the collection was given to the Music Library by Nils Vigeland, executor of Smit's estate.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Alternate Forms
Collection contents have been digitized in part and are available in UBdigit.
Biographical Note
Leo Smit was born to Russian immigrants on January 12, 1921, in Philadelphia. He received his earliest musical training from his father, Kolman Smit, beginning at age five. Kolman Smit was a professional violinist who performed in the Philadelphia Orchestra (1926-1931) under Leopold Stokowski, the Cincinnati Symphony under Fritz Reiner, and the NBC Symphony under Arturo Toscanini.
After private piano studies with Martha Lantner, Joseph Wissof, and Bert Shefter, Smit traveled to Moscow with his mother in 1929 to study piano for three months with Dmitri Kabalevsky on scholarship at the Moscow Conservatory. Upon his return to Philadelphia, Smit received a scholarship in 1930 to study piano at Curtis Institute of Music with noted piano pedagogue Isabelle Vengerova. He continued his studies on scholarship in New York, studying piano with José Iturbi (1933-35) and composition with Nicolas Nabokov (1935). It was under Nabokov's tutelage that Smit produced his first original composition in 1935, Zvay, a song setting of a Yiddish poem by Mani Loeb for soprano and piano.
Smit began his professional career as a pianist while still in his teens. His first professional engagement was as rehearsal pianist for George Balanchine's American Ballet Company in 1936-37. A year after beginning in this position, Smit met Igor Stravinsky during rehearsals of the composer's ballet, Jeu de Cartes. Smit gave his debut recital as a solo pianist at Carnegie Hall in February 1939. His successful debut was followed by a concert tour of the United States in 1940.
Leo Smit's career as composer, pianist, conductor, and educator spanned seven decades of musical life in the United States. He established close working relationships, and/or friendships, with many of the most prominent musicians of the 20th century, including Igor Stravinsky, Béla Bartók, Aaron Copland, Leonard Bernstein, Harold Shapero, William Schuman, Alex Haieff, Leopold Stokowski, and Lukas Foss. As a performer, Smit was an enthusiastic and persuasive advocate and interpreter of the music of his time, especially the solo piano music of Aaron Copland. His compositional output totals more than one hundred works, including two operas, three symphonies, more than ninety songs, two ballets, and numerous chamber and piano works.
Smit was also a talented photographer. In addition to the many photographs he took of noted musicians, Smit also used his skill as a photographer to capture images from his travels. Many of his travel pictures reflect his reverence for nature. As part of his innovative approach to programming, Smit would often include displays of his photography in his theme-based concerts.
During his career Leo Smit earned several awards and honors, including Fulbright (piano) and Guggenheim (composition) Fellowships in 1950, a fellowship at the American Academy in Rome for 1950-51, the Boston Symphony Merit Award in 1953 for his Symphony No. 1 (premiered October 16, 1953 by the Boston Symphony Orchestra, conducted by Charles Munch), the New York Critics Circle Award in 1957 (also for his Symphony No. 1), his selection as an artist for a State Department concert tour of Latin America in 1967-68, and the Buffalo Evening News Man of the Year award in 1969. As an educator, Smit held positions at Sarah Lawrence College (1947-49), UCLA (1957-63), and the State University of New York at Buffalo (1962-84).
Leo Smit died December 12, 1999 in Scripps Hospital, Encinitas, California.
Scope and Content Note
The Leo Smit Photograph Collection consists of a mixture of photographs documenting Smit's life. These include images of Smit as a child and young man, photographs with friends and colleagues, including Aaron Copland, Pete Johnson, Leonard Bernstein, and Sir Fred Hoyle, photographs documenting Smit's tour of Latin America 1967-1968, portraits of Smit, and images of scenes from Smit's chamber opera, Magic Water. The collection also includes several photographs by Leo Smit. These include images of Leonard Bernstein, William Schuman, members of the University at Buffalo Music Department (including Morton Feldman), and members of the Buffalo Sabres hockey team, as well as photographs of Smit's collection of Kachina dolls. Portraits by other photographers include those of Aaron Copland, Pete Johnson, and Smit's father, Kolman Smit. There is also a single postcard portrait of composer Peter Ilyich Tchaikovsky and a single reproduction of a photograph of Franz Liszt. Some items in the collection have been dated according to date stamps on the image verso. These are most likely more reflective of when a print was made rather than when it was shot.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in nine series:
I. Photographs of Leo Smit, with and without other people. Arranged in approximate chronological order.
II. Photographs of people and places without Leo Smit. Arranged alphabetically by name of subject.
III. Photographs by Leo Smit of a 1976 hockey game between the Buffalo Sabres and the New York Rangers.
IV. Photographs by Leo Smit of Istanbul, Turkey.
V. Photographs of Leo Smit's collection of Kachina dolls.
VI. Postcard portrait of Peter Ilyich Tchaikovsky.
VII. Photographs by Leo Smit of faculty members of the University at Buffalo Music Department taken at a retreat April 9, 1975 at the First Presbyterian Church, Buffalo, N.Y.
VIII. Negatives for photographs in the collection.
IX. Oversized color portrait of Leo Smit (2 copies).
X. Additional photographs
Container List
- Photographs of Leo Smit, with and without other people 1926-1998, I.; Items 1-78
  Arranged in approximate chronological order.
  - Leo Smit at 5 years old, 1926, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item smit001)
  - Leo Smit at 9 years old, 1930, 1 photograph; Eisenburg, Maurice (Box 1, Item smit002)
  - Leo Smit at 15 years old, 1936, 1 photograph; Astor Studio (Astoria, Long Island) (Box 1, Item smit003)
  - Leo Smit at age 17 years old, 1938, 1 photograph; Talbot (New York City) (Box 1, Item smit004)
  - Leo Smit at age 17 years, 1938, 1 photograph; Talbot (New York City) (Box 1, Item smit005)
  - Leo Smit at age 17 years, 1938, 1 photograph; Talbot (New York City) (Box 1, Item smit006)
  - Leo Smit (center) with Igor Stravinsky, 1936, 1 photograph; Schaal, Eric (Box 1, Item smit007)
  - Leo Smit (left) with Igor Stravinsky, 1936, 1 photograph; Schaal, Eric (Box 1, Item smit008)
  - Leo Smit with Benny Goodman, 1950, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item smit009)
  - Leo Smit at piano, 195-?, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item smit010)
  - Leo Smit with Aaron Copland, 1958, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item smit011)
  - Leo Smit's hands at piano keyboard, ca. 1965, 1 photograph; Smith, Gordon S (Box 1, Item smit012)
  - Leo Smit with Pete Johnson, 1966?, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item smit013)
  - Leo Smit (at piano) in recital at the National Conservatory of Music, Santo Domingo, March 8, 1967, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item smit014)
  - Leo Smit (at piano) at National Conservatory of Music, Santo Domingo, March 8, 1967, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item smit015)
  - Leo Smit (at piano) at National Conservatory of Music, Santo Domingo, March 8, 1967, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item smit016)
  - Leo Smit lecturing at National Conservatory of Music, Santo Domingo, March 8, 1967, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item smit017)
  - Leo Smit with student at National Conservatory of Music, Santo Domingo, March 8, 1967, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item smit018)
  - Leo Smit with student at National Conservatory of Music, Santo Domingo, March 8, 1967, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item smit019)
  - Leo Smit at piano at National Conservatory of Music, Santo Domingo, March 8, 1967, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item smit020)
  - Leo Smit at piano at National Conservatory of Music, Santo Domingo, March 8, 1967, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item smit021)
  - Leo Smit at piano at National Conservatory of Music, Santo Domingo, March 8, 1967, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item smit022)
  - Leo Smit with students at National Conservatory of Music, Santo Domingo, March 8, 1967, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item smit023)
  - Leo Smit at piano, April 1967, 1 photograph; Foto India (Asuncion, Paraguay) (Box 1, Item smit024)
  - Leo Smit reading a lecture at Asuncion Bi-National Center, April 1967, 1 photograph; Foto India (Asuncion, Paraguay) (Box 1, Item smit025)
  - Leo Smit at piano with students at Asuncion Bi-National Center, April 1967, 1 photograph; Foto India (Asuncion, Paraguay) (Box 1, Item smit026)
  - Leo Smit at piano at Asuncion Bi-National Center, April 1967, 1 photograph; Foto India (Asuncion, Paraguay) (Box 1, Item smit027)
  - Leo Smit at piano at Asuncion Bi-National Center, April 1967, 1 photograph; Foto India (Asuncion, Paraguay) (Box 1, Item smit028)
  - Leo Smit at piano before audience at Asuncion Bi-National Center, April 1967, 1 photograph; Foto India (Asuncion, Paraguay) (Box 1, Item smit029)
  - Leo Smit with Gladys Vallejo at Asuncion Bi-National Center, April 1967, 1 photograph; Foto India (Asuncion, Paraguay) (Box 1, Item smit030)
  - Leo Smit at piano at Asuncion Bi-National Center, April 1967, 1 photograph; Foto India (Asuncion, Paraguay) (Box 1, Item smit031)
  - Leo Smit with dignitaries at Asuncion Bi-National Center, April 1967, 1 photograph; Foto India (Asuncion, Paraguay) (Box 1, Item smit032)
  - Leo Smit with dignitaries at Asuncion Bi-National Center, April 1967, 1 photograph; Foto India (Asuncion, Paraguay) (Box 1, Item smit033)
  - Leo Smit with dignitaries at Asuncion Bi-National Center, April 1967, 1 photograph; Foto India (Asuncion, Paraguay) (Box 1, Item smit034)
  - Leo Smit at piano, 1967, 1 photograph; Foto Miguel (Brazil) (Box 1, Item smit035)
  - Six local musicians on 1967-68 Latin American tour, 1967-68, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item smit036)
  - Leo Smit with Ambassador Clarence Boonstra at reception for Costa Rican writers and national arts prizewinners, April 21, 1968, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item smit037)
  - Leo Smit with Ambassador Clarence Boonstra at reception for Costa Rican writers and national arts prizewinners, April 21, 1968, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item smit038)
  - Leo Smit at piano before audience at National Conservatory, April 25, 1968, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item smit039)
  - Leo Smit being greeted at La Paz airport, March 25, 1968, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item smit040)
  - Leo Smit being greeted at La Paz airport, March 25, 1968, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item smit041)
  - Leo Smit at La Paz airport, March 25, 1968, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item smit042)
  - Proof sheet with three images of Leo Smit at piano, ca. 1968, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item smit043)
  - Proof sheet with 27 images of Leo Smit alone at piano and 6 with students, ca. 1968, 1 proof sheet; Unidentified (Box 1, Item smit044)
  - Leo Smit at piano, 1960's, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item smit045)
  - Leo Smit at piano, 1960's, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item smit046)
  - Leo Smit at piano, 1960's, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item smit047)
  - Leo Smit portrait, 1960s, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item smit048)
  - Leo Smit portrait, 1960's, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item smit049)
  - Leo Smit performing his Piano Concerto with Buffalo Philharmonic, Nov. 1968, 1 photograph; Tuttle, Jim (Box 1, Item smit050)
  - Leo Smit performing his Piano Concerto with Buffalo Philharmonic, Lukas Foss conducting, Nov. 1968, 1 photograph; Tuttle, Jim (Box 1, Item smit051)
  - Leo Smit, after performing his Piano Concerto with Buffalo Philharmonic, Lukas Foss conducting, Nov. 1968, 1 photograph; Tuttle, Jim (Box 1, Item smit052)
  - Leo Smit giving a lecture, ca. 1970?, 1 photograph; SUNY Buffalo Audio-Visual Center (Box 1, Item smit053)
  - Leo Smit with Sir Fred Hoyle at premiere of Smit's Copernicus, 1973, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item smit054)
  - Leo Smit with Sir Fred Hoyle at piano, ca. 1970, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item smit055)
  - Leo Smit portrait, ca. 1970, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item smit057)
  - Leo Smit at piano, ca. 1970, 1 photograph; Ursillo, Catherine (Box 1, Item smit058)
  - University at Buffalo production of Leo Smit's chamber opera, Magic Water, October 29-30, 1979, 1 photograph; Haupt, Irene (Box 1, Item smit059)
  - University at Buffalo production of Leo Smit's chamber opera, Magic Water, October 29-30, 1979, 1 photograph; Haupt, Irene (Box 1, Item smit060)
  - University at Buffalo production of Leo Smit's chamber opera, Magic Water, October 29-30, 1979, 1 photograph; Haupt, Irene (Box 1, Item smit061)
  - Leo Smit conducting University at Buffalo production of his chamber opera, Magic Water, October 29-30, 1979, 1 photograph; Haupt, Irene (Box 1, Item smit062)
  - Leo Smit conducting University at Buffalo production of his chamber opera, Magic Water, October 29-30,1979, 1 photograph; Haupt, Irene (Box 1, Item smit063)
  - Leo Smit portrait, circa 1979, 1 photograph; Houghton, Jim (Box 2, Item smit064)
  - Leo Smit portrait, circa 1979, 1 photograph; Houghton, Jim (Box 2, Item smit065)
  - Leo Smit portrait, circa 1979, 1 photograph; Houghton, Jim (Box 2, Item smit066)
  - Leo Smit portrait, circa 1979, 1 photograph; Houghton, Jim (Box 2, Item smit067)
  - Leo Smit portrait, in Rome?, circa 1979, 1 photograph; Kaish, Luize (?) (Box 2, Item smit068)
  - Leo Smit portrait, in Rome?, circa 1979, 1 photograph; Kaish, Luize (?) (Box 2, Item smit069)
  - Leo Smit portrait, in Rome?, circa 1979, 1 photograph; Kaish, Luize (?) (Box 2, Item smit070)
  - Leo Smit portrait, in Rome?, circa 1979, 1 photograph; Kaish, Luize (?) (Box 2, Item smit071)
  - Leo Smit with Aaron Copland in Copland's studio, 1979, 1 photograph; Houghton, Jim (Box 2, Item smit072)
  - Leo Smit with Aaron Copland and Leonard Bernstein backstage at Kennedy Center, Copland 80th birthday concert, November 14, 1980, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item smit073)
  - Leo Smit, Rosalynn Carter, Aaron Copland, President Jimmy Carter, Leonard Bernstein, and Mstislav Rostropovich - Copland 80th birthday concert, November 14, 1980, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item smit074)
  - Leo Smit with Aaron Copland at Copland 80th birthday concert, November 16, 1980, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item smit075)
  - Leo Smit self portrait, circa 1967, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit076)
  - Leo Smit in chair, 1980, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item smit077)
  - Leo Smit, circa 1998, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item smit078)
- Photographs of people and places without Leo Smit circa 1936-1977, II.; Items 79-91
  Arranged alphabetically by name of subject.
  - Leonard Bernstein conducting at the Vatican, 1973, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit079)
  - Frederick Burgomaster, conductor, organist, Jan. 10, 1977, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit080)
  - Aaron Copland conducting, 1968?, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item smit081)
  - Martha Herr Hanneman, soprano, Jan. 10, 1977, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit082)
  - Pete Johnson signing autographs, 1966?, 1 photograph; SUNY Buffalo Audio-Visual Center (Box 2, Item smit083)
  - Pete Johnson portrait, 1966?, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item smit084)
  - Pete Johnson portrait with inscription, 1966, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item smit085)
  - Carol Plantamura, soprano, Jan. 10, 1977, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit086)
  - Heinz Rehfuss, baritone, Jan. 10, 1977, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit087)
  - Suze Leal Rehfuss, mezzo-soprano, Jan. 10, 1977, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit088)
  - William Schuman, 1960s?, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit089)
  - Kolman Smit (Leo Smit's father), violin, with Leo Smit in background, ca. 1936-1938, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item smit090)
  - Henrik Svitzer, flutist, Jan. 10, 1977, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit091)
- Photographs by Leo Smit of 1976 hockey game between the Buffalo Sabres and New York Rangers 1976, III.; Items 92-99
  Randomly arranged.
  - Buffalo Sabres player Gilbert Perreault on bench, 1976, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit092)
  - Buffalo Sabres player Don Luce (no. 20), 1976, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit093)
  - Buffalo Sabres player Rick Martin, with no. 22 Jocelyn Guevremont in background, 1976, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit094)
  - Proof sheet of 20 images of Buffalo Sabres/New York Rangers game, 1976, 1976, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit095)
  - Faceoff with Rangers no. 77 Phil Esposito, Danny Gare (18), Jerry Korab (4), Terry Martin (25), Jim Schoenfeld (6), 1976, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit096)
  - Buffalo Sabres shot on Rangers goalie, 1976, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit097)
  - Male and female couple at Buffalo Sabres game, 1976, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit098)
  - Buffalo Sabres player Jerry Korab on ice, 1976, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit099)
- Photographs by Leo Smit of Istanbul, Turkey circa 1979, IV.; Items 100-102
  - Topkapi Sarayi Muzesi, Istanbul, Turkey, interior view, circa 1979, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit100)
  - Blue Mosque, Istanbul, Turkey, interior view, circa 1979, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit101)
  - Minaret, Istanbul, Turkey, circa 1979, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit102)
- Photographs of Leo Smit's collection of Kachina dolls circa 1980-1989, V.; Items 103-115
  - Kachina dolls, circa 1980-1989, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit103)
  - Kachina dolls, circa 1980-1989, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit104)
  - Kachina dolls, circa 1980-1989, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit105)
  - Kachina dolls, circa 1980-1989, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit106)
  - Kachina doll, circa 1980-1989, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit107)
  - Kachina dolls, circa 1980-1989, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit108)
  - Kachina dolls, circa 1980-1989, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit109)
  - Kachina doll, circa 1980-1989, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit110)
  - Kachina dolls, circa 1980-1989, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit111)
  - Kachina dolls, circa 1980-1989, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit112)
  - Kachina dolls, circa 1980-1989, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit113)
  - Kachina dolls, circa 1980-1989, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit114)
  - Kachina dolls, circa 1980-1989, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit115)
- Portrait postcard of Peter Ilyich Tchaikovsky circa 1890, VI.; Item 116
  - Portrait postcard of Peter Ilyich Tchaikovsky, circa 1890, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item smit116)
- Photographs by Leo Smit of faculty members of the University at Buffalo music department taken at a retreat held at the First Presbyterian Church, Buffalo, N.Y. April 9 1975, VII.; Items 117-146
  - Unidentified person, April 19, 1975, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit117)
  - Sylvia Dimiziani, April 9, 1975, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit118)
  - Unidentified person and Stephen Manes, April 9, 1975, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit119)
  - Morton Feldman, April 9, 1975, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit120)
  - Morton Feldman, April 9, 1975, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit121)
  - David Kuen, April 9, 1975, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit122)
  - Morton Feldman and Edmund Strainchamps, April 9, 1975, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit123)
  - Unidentified person, April 9, 1975, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit124)
  - Unidentified person and Muriel Wolf, April 9, 1975, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit125)
  - Livingston Gearhart, April 9, 1975, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit126)
  - Edmund Strainchamps, April 9, 1975, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit127)
  - Edmund Strainchamps, April 9, 1975, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit128)
  - Harriet Simons, April 9, 1975, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit129)
  - Allen Sigel, April 9, 1975, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit130)
  - Ed Gordon, Frina Boldt, and James McKinnon, April 9, 1975, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit131)
  - William Thomson and Ted Mayer, April 9, 1975, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit132)
  - Carlo Pinto, April 9, 1975, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit133)
  - Unidentified person, April 9, 1975, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit134)
  - Robert Mols, April 9, 1975, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit135)
  - James McKinnon and Lejaren Hiller, April 9, 1975, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit136)
  - Heinz Rehfuss, April 9, 1975, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit137)
  - Charlotte Roederer, April 9, 1975, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit138)
  - Heinz Rehfuss, April 9, 1975, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit139)
  - Muriel Wolf and Sylvia Dimiziani, April 9, 1975, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit140)
  - Unidentified male and Charlotte Roederer, April 9, 1975, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit141)
  - Frina Boldt, April 9, 1975, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit142)
  - Robert Mols, April 9, 1975, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit143)
  - David Fuller?, April 9, 1975, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit144)
  - Robert Mols, Harriet Simons, Sylvia Dimiziani, April 9, 1975, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit145)
  - Unidentified person, April 9, 1975, 1 photograph; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit146)
- Negatives for photographs in the collection circa 1926-1989, VIII.; Items 147-149
  - Negatives for photographs of Buffalo Sabres game, 1976, 8 negatives; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit147)
  - 16 negatives of photographs from the Leo Smit estate, all printed for this collection, 1926-1999, 16 negatives (Box 2, Item smit148)